Prabhaaharan Rajavel

Research Engineer

2/685, vivekanandar 7th Street, S R Nagar South. Tirupur 641687

+919047090419

in Prabhaaharan Rajavel

praba-stackoverflow

Self-directed and result-driven research engineer professional with a comprehensive background in the design and development of AI applications. Have a strong fundamental in machine learning and software development. Built countable number of AI proof of concepts (POC) and delivered a minimum viable product (MVP) in predictive analytics. Experience in solving problems in healthcare industry and the development of HIPAA compliant healthcare products.

WORK EXPERIENCE

BUDDI.AI (July 2020 - Present) Research Engineer

- · Currently working in automating parts of revenue cycle management. Solving medical language problem in clinical and pharma domains.
- · Have a great experience in natural and medical language processing. Closely work with research scientists to productize proprietary machine learning algorithms.

BUDDI.AI (July 2019 - June 2020)

Junior Research Engineer

- Built a predictive analytics platform-BUDDIMake.Ai for the manufacturing sector. The platform helped to predict the manufactured product failure and thus improved production yield of the company by 3%.
- Designed and developed a medical-language processing platform which automates major parts of revenue-cycle-management in US
- · Closely worked with a research scientist to experiment in new ML research ideas in various types of data.

BUDDI.AI (December 2018 - June 2019) Research Intern

- · Worked on benchmarking of top-notch GPUs and Intel FPGAs for computationally expensive DL problems.
- · Benchmarked various metrics and reported Intel with brief results. Experience in OpenCL programming and kernel (GPU) level runtime
- Worked on a highly scalable predictive analytics platform BUDDIMake.Ai.

TCS-Centre of Excellance (June 2018 - August 2018) Software Intern

- Worked on the deployment of OpenStack cloud services in CentOS.
- Deployed CirrOS, a tiny OS in OpenStack cloud and implemented a small java-microservice.

EDUCATION

Thiagarajar College of Engineering

Bachelor's Degree Electrical & Electronics Engineering

(June 2015 - May 2019)

December 2018

(October 2019 - December 2020)

8.51

PROJECTS

Predictive Analytics Platform

https://www.automotiv.ai/views/buddimake.html

Manufacturing Analytics Platform

SKILLS CERTIFICATIONS

Intermediate

Scala **Pvthon** Machine Learning

Intermediate Intermediate Cousera

Machine Learning Management **Neural Networks And Deep Learning** August 2020 Intermediate Proficient DeepLearning.Ai

NLP & Text Analysis Neo4i

Play Framework Time Series Analysis Intermediate Novice

JavaScript

Novice

AWARDS

Intermediate

Winner IoT Contest 2018 February 2018

Texas Instruments

Caterpillar Innovate award First Tech Challenge

June 2017

Winning Alliance award First Tech Challenge June 2017

Caterpillar